<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OSCAR </title>
    <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on OSCAR </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 09:10:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oscar.grycap.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design of workflows across OSCAR services with Node-RED (Part 2).</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-node-red-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 09:10:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-node-red-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In this post, the work with Node-RED and its interaction with OSCAR services will be continued.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of workflows across OSCAR services with Node-RED (Part 1).</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-node-red/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-node-red/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will be explaining the integration of Node-RED software with OSCAR. The necessary tools will be given to achieve workflows between OSCAR and Node-RED simply and intuitively through flow-based programming techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use COMPSs with OSCAR</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-guide-to-use-compss-in-oscar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-guide-to-use-compss-in-oscar/</guid>
      <description>This is a tutorial to integrate COMPSs with OSCAR. In this post, we will explain what COMPSs is and the integration with OSCAR to support parallel processing within an on-premises serverless platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invoking an OSCAR Service from an EGI Jupyter Notebook</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-egi-notebooks-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-egi-notebooks-integration/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we are going to showcase the usage of the OSCAR Python API, implemented to interact with OSCAR clusters and its services through EGI Notebooks, a tool based on Jupyter for data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why use OSCAR as a serverless AI/ML model inference platform?</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-reasons-oscar-for-ai-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-reasons-oscar-for-ai-inference/</guid>
      <description>What is OSCAR? OSCAR is an open-source serverless platform for event-driven data-processing containerized applications that execute on elastic Kubernetes clusters that are dynamically provisioned on multiple Clouds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User interfaces with Gradio for AI model inference in OSCAR services</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-visualize-oscar-service-with-gradio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-visualize-oscar-service-with-gradio/</guid>
      <description>What is Gradio? Gradio is a Python library for building user web interfaces for Machine Learning (ML) applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FDL Composer to create a workflow with OSCAR</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-fdl-composer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-fdl-composer/</guid>
      <description>FDL-Composer is a tool to visually design workflows for OSCAR and SCAR. We are going to simulate the example video-process</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OSCAR as a FaaS platform for synchronous inference of a machine learning model</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-faas-sync-ml-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-faas-sync-ml-inference/</guid>
      <description>This guide aims to show the usage of the OSCAR platform for Machine Learning inference using a pre-trained Convolutional Neural network classification model by DEEP-Hybrid-DataCloud: the Plants species classifier, to classify plant pictures by specie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide to create a service in OSCAR</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-guide-to-use-oscar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-guide-to-use-oscar/</guid>
      <description>This is a step by step guide to show developers how to create their first service in OSCAR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Convert Text to Speech with OSCAR</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-text-to-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-text-to-speech/</guid>
      <description>This use case implements text-to-speech transformation using the OSCAR serverless platform, where an input of plain text returns an audio file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Serverless Cloud-to-Edge Computing Continuum Approach for Edge AI inference</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-cloud-to-edge-approach-for-edge-ai-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-cloud-to-edge-approach-for-edge-ai-inference/</guid>
      <description>OSCAR is an open-source framework for data-processing serverless computing. Users upload files to an object storage which invokes a function responsible for processing each file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OSCAR as a FaaS platform for scalable asynchronous inference of a machine learning model</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-faas-scalable-ml-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-faas-scalable-ml-inference/</guid>
      <description>OSCAR is a framework to efficiently support on-premises FaaS (Functions as a Service) for general-purpose file-processing computing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deployment of an OSCAR cluster in the EGI Federated Cloud</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-serverless-egi-federated-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-serverless-egi-federated-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Here we present a step by step guide to help you deploy an OSCAR cluster in the EGI Federated Cloud, specifically in the EOSC-Synergy VO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-driven inference of AI models for mask detection with the OSCAR serverless platform</title>
      <link>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-serverless-ai-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 10:07:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oscar.grycap.net/blog/post-oscar-serverless-ai-models/</guid>
      <description>What is OSCAR? OSCAR is an open-source platform to support the Functions as a Service (FaaS) computing model for file-processing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
